Viveka Jayaprakash

Software Tester(Immediate Joinee)

4+ years work experience as a software test engineer in an agile development environment for Web applications in the Tax related forms. Responsible for test strategies and test cases to cover the entire logic to provide a high quality application.



vivekajd@gmail.com 🔀

9786055220

Coimbatore, India 👂

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance

Ivtl Infoview Technologies Pvt Ltd., Chennai

02/2019 - 09/2020

Project: HUE/ Payroll Management(Tax Forms related)

Tasks

- Reviewed the code standards for both front end and back end.
- Analyzed the code defects and failures and presented code refraction and design failure.
- As a final step of review the code standards are examined and solutions have been provided to the developers in order create effectiveness in code.

Code Evaluator

Ivtl Infoview Technologies Pvt Ltd., Chennai

07/2017 - 01/2019

Project: HUE/Commuter Transportation Fee(Sales)

Tasks

- Reviewed the code standards for both front end and back end.
- Analyzed the code defects and failures and presented code refraction and design failure.
- Created testcases related to the defects and meet the standards and avoid further errors to make the code and UI efficient.

Junior Engineer

Ivtl Infoview Technologies Pvt Ltd.,

06/2016 - 06/2017

Tasks

- Full stack development of ERP Web Application converted from Desktop application using DWR framework.
- Studied corrections from senior engineers to learn and grow professionally.
- Version Control: Git, Build Tool: Mavan, Server: Tomcat, DB:

 Oracle
- Environment: XML, CSS, Java, JavaScript.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Information TechnologyInfo Institute of Technology, Coimbatore

08/2012 - 04/2016

Graduated with 7.81 CGPA

SKILLS

Java EE and Java SE

Core Java

Google Closure Js

 XML

HTML

QA Testing

Reliable testcase creation

Flexible Testcases that can even be used by freshers

SDLC & STLC flows, Unit testing, UI Testing, API testing, SQL queries

Testcase execution

Selenium

DataDriven, POM and Keyword driven frameworks of Selenium

TestNG

CERTIFICATIONS

Course on Core Java

BETA Technologies INDIA Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore

Course on DOT NET

BETA Technologies INDIA Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore

Workshop on Cloud Computing

Technophilia systems

Workshop on IBM BLUEMIX

Propulsion Technologies, Coimbatore

ACHIEVEMENTS

Code and UI Evaluation Trainer

Based on my responsibility, I had an opportunity to train Evaluators and Developers to inculcate the importance of code quality, the basic code standards and to avoid the framework and common issues.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

PERSONAL SKILLS

Observer

TeamWork

Leadership Quality

Flexibility